<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-01T07:06:14-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Raphaël Attias</title><subtitle>Research Intern @ NEC Laboratories 🇺🇸. Master Student in Data Science from EPFL 🇨🇭.</subtitle><author><name>Raphaël Attias</name><email>raphael.attias@outlook.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Survey of supervised and unsupervised data augmentation techniques in cancer cell nucleus detection for Deep Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2021/12/ganwriting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Survey of supervised and unsupervised data augmentation techniques in cancer cell nucleus detection for Deep Learning" /><published>2022-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2021/12/NEC</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2021/12/ganwriting/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internship, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Currently, I am working as a research and software intern at NEC Laboratories in Princeton, a brilliant research company along with world-renowned scientists. I have implemented and researched the various techniques of data augmentation to improve results on a complex multi-class segmentation problem. In the Medical Machine Learning department, I motivated the use of GANs to produce new samples for cancer detection, and explored the use of self-supervised method such as MixMatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cell.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Raphaël Attias</name><email>raphael.attias@outlook.com</email></author><category term="Machine Learning" /><category term="Computer Vision" /><category term="Self-Supervised" /><category term="GANs" /><category term="Medical" /><summary type="html">Internship, 2022 Currently, I am working as a research and software intern at NEC Laboratories in Princeton, a brilliant research company along with world-renowned scientists. I have implemented and researched the various techniques of data augmentation to improve results on a complex multi-class segmentation problem. In the Medical Machine Learning department, I motivated the use of GANs to produce new samples for cancer detection, and explored the use of self-supervised method such as MixMatch.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploration of D-Cliques Variations and Edges Cases for Decentralized Federated Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2021/12/federated-learning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploration of D-Cliques Variations and Edges Cases for Decentralized Federated Learning" /><published>2021-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2021/12/dcliques</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2021/12/federated-learning/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research Project, 90/100, 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Researched the decentralized implementation of a Federated Learning algorithm in the Scalable Computing Systems Laboratory at EPFL. Supervised by Prof. Karmarec, I explored and identify the computational implications of a Decentralized approach to a state-of-the-art topology (D-Cliques) in a research environment. D-Cliques (Bellet et al. 2021) is a recent approach to coordinate and structure a network for DFL. While a fully connected topology is not practical due to the number of edges increasing quadratically, D-Cliques provide an intuitive approach in providing locally fully connected neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/clique.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epfl.ch/labs/sacs/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Raphael_Master_Project.pdf&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--primary&quot;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Raphaël Attias</name><email>raphael.attias@outlook.com</email></author><category term="Machine Learning" /><category term="Federated Learning" /><summary type="html">Research Project, 90/100, 2021Researched the decentralized implementation of a Federated Learning algorithm in the Scalable Computing Systems Laboratory at EPFL. Supervised by Prof. Karmarec, I explored and identify the computational implications of a Decentralized approach to a state-of-the-art topology (D-Cliques) in a research environment. D-Cliques (Bellet et al. 2021) is a recent approach to coordinate and structure a network for DFL. While a fully connected topology is not practical due to the number of edges increasing quadratically, D-Cliques provide an intuitive approach in providing locally fully connected neighborhoods.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is the role of the media coverage in explaining stock market fluctuations?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2012/08/apple-stock/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is the role of the media coverage in explaining stock market fluctuations?" /><published>2021-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2012/08/apple</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2012/08/apple-stock/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applied Data Analysis class, 100/100&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; During this semester long project, we studied in a group of 4 the fluctuation of the Apple stock price, volume and its relationship with quotes in media. Using Yahoo API, Quotebank Dataset and web parsing, we show a visible and quantifiable correlation in Apple coverage and the price of its stock. This project contains a full introduction of the datasets, a study of meaningful events in Apple recent history and a fitted time series prediction taking into account the multiple results of the project. The results have been presented on an interactive website, which required knowledge in data visualization to tell our data story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/apple.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/raphaelattias/apple-stock-analytics&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--primary&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://thepandariders.com&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--primary&quot;&gt;Project Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Raphaël Attias</name><email>raphael.attias@outlook.com</email></author><category term="Data Science" /><summary type="html">Applied Data Analysis class, 100/100 During this semester long project, we studied in a group of 4 the fluctuation of the Apple stock price, volume and its relationship with quotes in media. Using Yahoo API, Quotebank Dataset and web parsing, we show a visible and quantifiable correlation in Apple coverage and the price of its stock. This project contains a full introduction of the datasets, a study of meaningful events in Apple recent history and a fitted time series prediction taking into account the multiple results of the project. The results have been presented on an interactive website, which required knowledge in data visualization to tell our data story.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Towards Robust and Adaptable Diagnosis of Pneumonia from Chest X-ray Data</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2012/08/robust-cxr/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Towards Robust and Adaptable Diagnosis of Pneumonia from Chest X-ray Data" /><published>2021-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2012/08/cxr</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2012/08/robust-cxr/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visual Intelligence, 90/100, 2021&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Artificial intelligence (AI) researchers and radiologists have recently reported AI systems that accurately diagnose pneumonia from a chest X-Ray images using deep neural networks when trained on a sufficient large and homogeneous amount of labelled images.
    However, the robustness and adaptability of these systems, trained minimizing the empirical risk (ERM), remains far way. In fact, ERM have no way of discard environment specific  features creating an alarming situation in which the systems appear accurate, but fail when tested in new hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/RoAdaNet.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/raphaelattias/pneumonia-diagnosis&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--primary&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/raphaelattias/pneumonia-diagnosis/blob/main/reports/Final%20Report.pdf&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--primary&quot;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Raphaël Attias</name><email>raphael.attias@outlook.com</email></author><category term="Machine Learning" /><category term="Self-Supervised" /><category term="Computer Vision" /><category term="GANs" /><category term="Medical" /><summary type="html">Visual Intelligence, 90/100, 2021 Artificial intelligence (AI) researchers and radiologists have recently reported AI systems that accurately diagnose pneumonia from a chest X-Ray images using deep neural networks when trained on a sufficient large and homogeneous amount of labelled images. However, the robustness and adaptability of these systems, trained minimizing the empirical risk (ERM), remains far way. In fact, ERM have no way of discard environment specific features creating an alarming situation in which the systems appear accurate, but fail when tested in new hospitals.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Implementation of GANWriting, Content-Conditioned Generation of Styled Handwritten Word Images</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2021/12/ganwriting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Implementation of GANWriting, Content-Conditioned Generation of Styled Handwritten Word Images" /><published>2021-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2021/12/ganwriting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2021/12/ganwriting/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internship, 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Worked on the deployment of a state-of-the-art GAN model for generating hand written words, with the goal of writing a full library in Pytorch Lightning. This framework relied on a deep understanding of Computer Vision and complex ML system.  GANWriting propose a novel method that is able to produce credible handwritten word images by conditioning the generative process with both calligraphic style features and textual content. The generator is guided by three complementary learning objectives: to produce realistic images, to imitate a certain handwriting style and to convey a specific textual content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ganwriting.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Raphaël Attias</name><email>raphael.attias@outlook.com</email></author><category term="Machine Learning" /><category term="Computer Vision" /><summary type="html">Internship, 2021 Worked on the deployment of a state-of-the-art GAN model for generating hand written words, with the goal of writing a full library in Pytorch Lightning. This framework relied on a deep understanding of Computer Vision and complex ML system. GANWriting propose a novel method that is able to produce credible handwritten word images by conditioning the generative process with both calligraphic style features and textual content. The generator is guided by three complementary learning objectives: to produce realistic images, to imitate a certain handwriting style and to convey a specific textual content.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Discussion on the viability of a modern Second Order Method in Non-Convex Optimization training a Deep Convolutional Neural Network</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/adahessian/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Discussion on the viability of a modern Second Order Method in Non-Convex Optimization training a Deep Convolutional Neural Network" /><published>2021-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/adahessian</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/adahessian/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimization for ML, 100/100, 2021&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Second order algorithms are among the most powerful optimization algorithms with superior convergence properties as compared to first order methods such as SGD and Adam. However computing or approximating the curvature matrix can be very expensive both in per-iteration computation time and memory cost. In this study we analyze the convenience in using a state-of-the-art Second Order Method (AdaHessian) in Non-Convex Optimization training a Deep Convolutional Neural Network (ResNet18) on MNIST database comparing with traditional First Order Methods. Advantages and disadvantages of both the methods are discussed and a final hybrid method combining the advantages of both is proposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ada.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/raphaelattias/adahessian&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--primary&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Raphaël Attias</name><email>raphael.attias@outlook.com</email></author><category term="Machine Learning" /><summary type="html">Optimization for ML, 100/100, 2021 Second order algorithms are among the most powerful optimization algorithms with superior convergence properties as compared to first order methods such as SGD and Adam. However computing or approximating the curvature matrix can be very expensive both in per-iteration computation time and memory cost. In this study we analyze the convenience in using a state-of-the-art Second Order Method (AdaHessian) in Non-Convex Optimization training a Deep Convolutional Neural Network (ResNet18) on MNIST database comparing with traditional First Order Methods. Advantages and disadvantages of both the methods are discussed and a final hybrid method combining the advantages of both is proposed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Study of California Highway Patrol data on 10 millions records using Oracle SQL</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/dbs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Study of California Highway Patrol data on 10 millions records using Oracle SQL" /><published>2021-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/dbs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/dbs/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databases Systems, 82/100, 2021&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; In this project we design the database schema and implement the relational schema, load the data into a DBMS, evaluate and optimize queries with query plan analysis in order to analyze the performance impact in Oracle SQL. The dataset contains a subset of data from the California Highway Patrol collected from the Statewide Integrated Traffic Records System (SWITRS), covering traffic collisions in the state of California in 2018. These reports have been collected by the Highway Patrol, recorded electronically for archival and preservation based on the forms filed by officers. This data has an immense value for urban planners and scientists that may want to analyze risks and how to improve the traffic situation and which factors or locations may be prevalent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ada.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Raphaël Attias</name><email>raphael.attias@outlook.com</email></author><category term="Data Science" /><summary type="html">Databases Systems, 82/100, 2021 In this project we design the database schema and implement the relational schema, load the data into a DBMS, evaluate and optimize queries with query plan analysis in order to analyze the performance impact in Oracle SQL. The dataset contains a subset of data from the California Highway Patrol collected from the Statewide Integrated Traffic Records System (SWITRS), covering traffic collisions in the state of California in 2018. These reports have been collected by the Highway Patrol, recorded electronically for archival and preservation based on the forms filed by officers. This data has an immense value for urban planners and scientists that may want to analyze risks and how to improve the traffic situation and which factors or locations may be prevalent.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Robust Journey Planning for CFF Zurich</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/adahessian/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Robust Journey Planning for CFF Zurich" /><published>2021-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/journey-planner</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/adahessian/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Labs in Data Science, 100/100, Best Class Project, 2021&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Developed and deployed a journey planner using Spark to compute and visualize the best transportation and path using Zurich Transportation System. Using CFF data, we built a predictive model that solved efficiently the transportation problem. Given a desired arrival time, our route planner will compute the fastest route between departure and arrival stops within a provided confidence tolerance expressed as interquartiles. For instance, “what route from A to B is the fastest at least Q% of the time if I want to arrive at B before instant T”. We used the Connection Scan Algorithm, handled data with and Hive PySpark and presented resutls with ipywidget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/61Nhfta.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/raphaelattias/lab-in-datascience&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--primary&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Raphaël Attias</name><email>raphael.attias@outlook.com</email></author><category term="Data Science" /><summary type="html">Labs in Data Science, 100/100, Best Class Project, 2021 Developed and deployed a journey planner using Spark to compute and visualize the best transportation and path using Zurich Transportation System. Using CFF data, we built a predictive model that solved efficiently the transportation problem. Given a desired arrival time, our route planner will compute the fastest route between departure and arrival stops within a provided confidence tolerance expressed as interquartiles. For instance, “what route from A to B is the fastest at least Q% of the time if I want to arrive at B before instant T”. We used the Connection Scan Algorithm, handled data with and Hive PySpark and presented resutls with ipywidget.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reinforcement Learning for moon landing in OpenGym</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/reinforcement-learning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reinforcement Learning for moon landing in OpenGym" /><published>2021-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/reinforcement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/reinforcement-learning/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial Neural Networks, 90/100, 2021&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Artificial intelligence (AI) researchers and radiologists have recently reported AI systems that accurately diagnose pneumonia from a chest X-Ray images using deep neural networks when trained on a sufficient large and homogeneous amount of labelled images.
    However, the robustness and adaptability of these systems, trained minimizing the empirical risk (ERM), remains far way. In fact, ERM have no way of discard environment specific  features creating an alarming situation in which the systems appear accurate, but fail when tested in new hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rl.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/raphaelattias/Deep-Reinforcement-Learning&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--primary&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Raphaël Attias</name><email>raphael.attias@outlook.com</email></author><category term="Machine Learning" /><summary type="html">Artificial Neural Networks, 90/100, 2021 Artificial intelligence (AI) researchers and radiologists have recently reported AI systems that accurately diagnose pneumonia from a chest X-Ray images using deep neural networks when trained on a sufficient large and homogeneous amount of labelled images. However, the robustness and adaptability of these systems, trained minimizing the empirical risk (ERM), remains far way. In fact, ERM have no way of discard environment specific features creating an alarming situation in which the systems appear accurate, but fail when tested in new hospitals.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Movie Recommendation System in Spark for Big Data</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/recommender/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Movie Recommendation System in Spark for Big Data" /><published>2021-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/movierecommender</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2014/08/recommender/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Systems for Data Science, 100/100, 2021&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Developed and deployed a movie recommendation system in Scala with Spark. The movie recommender is modeled with an approximate k-NN system that can predict efficiently over several machines the best movie for a user. The personalized recommender is implemented using modern libraries, such as Spark and written in Scala. The efficiency and economics are evaluated, and the model has been tested on multiple scale data sets and benchmarks, such as MovieLens 10M.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sds.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Raphaël Attias</name><email>raphael.attias@outlook.com</email></author><category term="Data Science" /><summary type="html">Systems for Data Science, 100/100, 2021 Developed and deployed a movie recommendation system in Scala with Spark. The movie recommender is modeled with an approximate k-NN system that can predict efficiently over several machines the best movie for a user. The personalized recommender is implemented using modern libraries, such as Spark and written in Scala. The efficiency and economics are evaluated, and the model has been tested on multiple scale data sets and benchmarks, such as MovieLens 10M.</summary></entry></feed>